Nicholas Pagonis

Resumé/CV





Introduction

Greetings! My name is Nicholas Pagonis. I currently attend John Septimus Roe Anglican Community School and enjoy improving my clinical expertise in First Aid during my spare time as well as heavily participating in the Scouting movement. After graduating from school, I intend to become a Special Operations Paramedic by studying at Curtin University and building my tactical knowledge with the Department of Fire and Emergency Services. From the age of 13, I obtained my Certificate of Resuscitation and followed the path of rescue by completing my Bronze Medallion with Royal Life Saving WA. I bring professionalism and quick response to the workplace and regularly act to gain these skills. To add, I am what's often referred to as a natural leader, meaning take charge of most situations unless instructed not to. I am applying to complete my practical hours at your swim school and then become a qualified swim instructor.

Education

John Septimus Roe Anglican 2007 - Present

Qualifications

Provide First Aid (HLTAID003)	16/06/2019
Certificate of Resuscitation	16/06/2019
Bronze Medalion	11/01/2019
Working with Children's Check	20/02/2019
National Police Clearance	27/12/2019

Skills

My skill range is very broad in the sense that I challenge myself in different areas consistently. I have developed various types of skills from Scouts which empower me in an outdoor domain, for example; rock climbing, abseiling, hiking, etc. The Scouting environment has also brought me very close to members of the State Emergency Service and has taught me different types of search and rescue techniques. On the opposite side of the spectrum, I am also very technologically inclined as you can see from my unique email address. Programs like Microsoft Word and Excel come very naturally to me in addition to other miscellaneous applications like Adobe Photoshop, which I am still a novice at. I am not only well educated in desktop programs but am also somewhat proficient in different code languages such as PHP, HTML and Javascript.

Commitments

State Emergency Service (Volunteer)

At the current point in time I am an Inductee with the Belmont SES Unit. I attend training once per week on a Monday evening. Any other commitments are unplanned and will only occur rarely in terms of a callout.

St John Cadet First Aider (Volunteer)

Similarly to the SES, I am an Inductee at this time and are currently awaiting to attend training.

Scouts WA (Volunteer)

Two evenings per week I attend the 1st Hampton Park Scout Group. On a Tuesday night I run my Venturer section as the Unit Leader and on Friday night I am a Youth Leader for the Scout section.

Nicholas Pagonis

Resumé/CV





Experience

The Entertainment Bank

Employee/Helper (Casual)

05/2018 - Present

The Entertainment Bank provides entertainment facilities for all ages but specifically for children. Activities like operating an Easter bunny suit or walk Santa around a shopping complex.

Hampton Park Scout Group

Unit Leader (Volunteer)

01/2018 - Present

As a Unit Leader, I ensure that activities and tasks are conducted in an appropriate manner as well as passing on knowledge to other Venturers.

Youth Leader (Volunteer)

11/2019 - Present

In Scouts there are 5 sections which are broken up into age increments. I am a youth leader in the Scout section (10-14 y.o) which means I have the same privileges as an adult leader and also the same responsibilities. What makes me a leader in Scouts is the ability to teach the youth new and useful skills that can bee used in their day to day life.

Scouts Australia YOU+LEAD Course

Participant 09/2019

In September, Scouts WA paid for my flight to Queensland to attend a national leadership course with participants all over the country. It was quite easily the best 5 days of my life. At the course we learnt leadership skills, relationship strategies and much more. For more details, contact the Assistant National Commissioner Youth Program, Johnathan Morey johnathan.morey@scouts.com.au

City of Stirling, Terry Tyzack Aquatic Centre

Prac Teacher (Volunteer)

01/2020 - Present

During the 2019-2020 summer holidays I completed the 2 day AUSTswim course and proceeded to begin the required practical hours. On the 7th of March I took the practical swimming assessment and passed with flying colours meaning I am now a qualified swimming instructor. From the end of January to the present day I have completed a multitude of hours in practical teaching and completed lesson plans to accompany my practical skills.